Guide to the Elmer J. Holland Papers, 1937-1968 AIS.1968.23
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Special Files, IV.
  - Subject File, 3.
    - Public Works. Economic Development (Box 294, Folder 5)
    - Publications requested for use in office (Box 294, Folder 6)
    - Publicity (Box 294, Folder 7)
    - The Pueblo Editorial (Box 294, Folder 8)
    - P -miscellaneous (Box 294, Folder 9)
    - Questionnaire to Pensioners, February 9, 1961 (Box 295, Folder 1)
    - Pensioner Questionnaires (Box 295, Folder 2)
    - Quie Amendment (Box 295, Folder 3)
    - R -general (Box 295, Folder 4-5)
    - Railroads (Box 295, Folder 6-7)
    - Railroads, 1962 (Box 295, Folder 8)
    - Railroad crossing. Old material (Box 295, Folder 9)
    - Railroad crossing elimination (Box 295, Folder 10)
    - Railroad correspondence general. Retirement, literature (Box 295, Folder 11)
    - Railroad crossing elimination legislation and McKeesport B&O project (Box 295, Folder 12)
    - Railroad legislation, letters, 1958 (Box 295, Folder 13)
    - Railroad retirement (Box 295, Folder 14)
    - Railroad retirement board (Box 295, Folder 15)
    - Reapportionment (Box 296, Folder 1-2)
    - General Pennsylvania Congressional Reapportionment (Box 296, Folder 2)
    - Reapportionment Pennsylvania (Box 296, Folder 3)
    - Reapportionment Supreme Court (Box 296, Folder 4)
    - Recommendations (Box 296, Folder 5-6)
    - Recreation (Box 296, Folder 7)
    - Referral Forms (Box 296, Folder 8)
    - Redevelopment Authority of Allegheny County (Box 297, Folder 1)
    - Republican Congressional Comm., 1960 (Box 298, Folder 1)
    - Republican Party. National Comm. (Box 298, Folder 2)
    - Republican Committee (Box 298, Folder 3)
    - Republican Policy (Box 298, Folder 4)
    - Requests beginning, 1968 (Box 299, Folder 1)
    - Requests, 1967 (Box 299, Folder 2)
    - Student request beginning, 1968 (Box 299, Folder 3)
    - Retirement (Box 299, Folder 4)
    - Retraining, 1963 (Box 299, Folder 5)
    - Retraining (Box 299, Folder 6-7)
    - Retraining and Education Clippings, 1963 (Box 300, Folder 1)
    - Retraining Program (Box 300, Folder 2)
    - Right to work (Box 300, Folder 3-5)
    - Rivers resources (Box 301, Folder 1)
    - Royal Typewriter (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - S-general (Box 301, Folder 3-4)
    - S-general -closed (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Salaries and allowances (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - Scholarships (Box 302, Folder 1-3)
    - Scholarships, 1961-1963 (Box 302, Folder 4)
    - Scholarships, 1963 (Box 302, Folder 5)
    - Scholarships, 1964 (Box 302, Folder 6)
    - Scholarships, 1965 (Box 302, Folder 7)
    - Scholarships, 1966 (Box 302, Folder 8)
    - Scholarship file, 1958-1960 (Box 303, Folder 1)
    - Scholarship and Loans, 1963 (Box 303, Folder 2)
    - Scholarships Fulbright (Box 303, Folder 3)
    - Schools (20th Congressional District) (Box 303, Folder 4)
    - School Dropout Program (Box 303, Folder 5)
    - Schools Honor students (Glassport Rotary Club Honors Dinner) (Box 303, Folder 6)
    - Schools Scholarships, etc. (Box 303, Folder 7)
    - Schools Honor Students. (McKeesport Rotarians banquet for Honor Students). (Box 303, Folder 8)
    - Scientists Working in Atomic Project and present missiles project (Box 303, Folder 9)
    - Scouts - Boy and Girl. (Box 303, Folder 10)
    - Scranton, William (Box 304, Folder 1)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission (Box 304, Folder 2)
    - Senior Citizen Letters, 1961 (Box 304, Folder 3)
    - Sewage Disposal (Box 304, Folder 4)
    - Shaffer, Raymond P. (Box 304, Folder 5)
    - Shapp, Milton (Box 304, Folder 6)
    - Short Work Week, 1962-1963 (Box 304, Folder 7)
    - Slovak (Box 304, Folder 8)
    - Small Business (Box 304, Folder 9)
    - Small Business Press Releases and Printed Matter (Box 305, Folder 1)
    - The 'Smith' Act (Box 305, Folder 2)
    - Social Security (Box 305, Folder 3)
    - Social Security Administration (Box 305, Folder 4)
    - Social Security Health Programs (Box 305, Folder 5)
    - Social Security and Medicare (Box 305, Folder 6)
    - Social Security Information (Box 305, Folder 7)
    - Social Security Material, speeches, etc., 1960 (Box 305, Folder 8)
    - Social Security (Box 305, Folder 9)
    - Social Security Pension (Box 305, Folder 10)
    - Social Security (Box 306, Folder 1-2)
    - South's Business Deals (Box 306, Folder 2)
    - Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission (Box 306, Folder 3-4)
    - Space (Box 306, Folder 5)
    - Spacemobile Information (Box 306, Folder 6)
    - Spotlight (Box 307, Folder 1)
    - Stamps Fort Duquesne Bicentennial Commemorative Stamps (Box 307, Folder 2)
    - Star Spangled Banner Mrs. Nichol (Box 307, Folder 3-4)
    - State Agencies (Box 307, Folder 5)
    - State Department (Box 307, Folder 6)
    - State Department, 1957-1960 (Box 307, Folder 7)
    - State Department, 1961-1962 (Box 307, Folder 8)
    - State Department Matters (Box 307, Folder 9)
    - State Department Printed material (Box 307, Folder 10)
    - Secretary of State Pictures and Biographies (Box 307, Folder 11)
    - Statements of EJH (Box 307, Folder 12)
    - State of the Union Address President Kennedy, January 30, 1961 (Box 307, Folder 13)
    - State Problems, 1963 (Box 308, Folder 1)
    - State Tech. Service (Box 308, Folder 2)
    - Steel correspondence (Box 308, Folder 3)
    - Steel, 1963 (Box 308, Folder 4)
    - Steel facts, 1962 (Box 308, Folder 5)
    - Steel, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 6)
    - Steel City Industrial Union Council (Box 308, Folder 7)
    - Steel Imports leg. (Box 308, Folder 8)
    - Steel Strike, 1959 (Box 309, Folder 1)
    - Steel Strike Material on, 1956 (Box 309, Folder 2)
    - Steel Strike, Letter to Fairless, 1952 (Box 309, Folder 3)
    - Steel Situation German and Japanese Imports (Box 309, Folder 4)
    - Steelworkers closing of National Tube Works McKeesport (Box 309, Folder 5)
    - Stockpiling (Box 309, Folder 6)
    - Steelworkers Resolutions Re Automation (Box 309, Folder 7)
    - Steelworkers Information (Box 309, Folder 8)
    - Supreme Court and Federal Courts (Box 310, Folder 1)
    - Surplus Food (Box 310, Folder 2-3)
    - Surplus Food, 1956-1960 (Box 310, Folder 4)
    - Surplus Food, 1961 (Box 310, Folder 5)
    - Surplus Good (Army, Navy, Govt. Surplus, etc.) (Box 310, Folder 6)
    - Surplus Goods and Property (Box 310, Folder 7)
    - Surplus Property printed matter (Box 310, Folder 8)
    - Sympathy (Box 310, Folder 9)
    - T-General (Box 311, Folder 1)
    - Taft Hartley Injunction on Strike, 1959 (Box 311, Folder 2)
    - Tamburitzans Duquesne University (Box 311, Folder 3)
    - Tax Depreciation (Box 311, Folder 4)
    - Taxes, 1962-1963 (Box 311, Folder 5)
    - State and Local Taxes, etc. (Box 311, Folder 6)
    - Tax Program, 1962 (Box 311, Folder 7)
    - Tax Program, 1963 (Box 311, Folder 8)
    - Teachers in 20th Congressional District, 1960 (Box 311, Folder 9)
    - Teachers list (Box 311, Folder 10)
    - Teachers' List Names and Addresses (Box 311, Folder 11)
    - Temple B'Nai Israel Sisterhood Membership, 1958-1959 (Box 311, Folder 12)
    - Tight Money Interest rates (Box 311, Folder 13)
    - Tour Information (Box 312, Folder 1)
    - Tours beginning 89th Congress, 1965 (Box 312, Folder 2)
    - Tours St. 'Henry's 8th Grade May 6, 7, 8th. (Box 312, Folder 3)
    - Tours St. Michaels April 13, 1964 (Box 312, Folder 4)
    - Tours Washington, D.C., 1962-1963 (Box 312, Folder 5)
    - Tours Washington, D.C. (Box 312, Folder 6)
    - Tours Washington (Box 312, Folder 7)
    - Washington Tours Boy Scout Troop No.267 (Box 312, Folder 8)
    - Trade World (Box 313, Folder 1)
    - Transportation (Box 313, Folder 2)
    - Transportation Department (Box 313, Folder 3)
    - Treasury Department (Box 313, Folder 4)
    - P.W. Trucks (Box 313, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Congress Joint Econ. Comm., 1966 (Box 313, Folder 6)
    - U -General (Box 314, Folder 1)
    - Ukrainian (Box 314, Folder 2)
    - Unamerican Activities Committee (Box 314, Folder 3)
    - Unemployment (Box 314, Folder 4)
    - Unemployment and the Impact of Automation original survey conducted in 1961 and report submitted to the President (Box 314, Folder 5)
    - Unemployment Compensation (Box 314, Folder 6)
    - Unemployment Insurance Information by Gov. Lawrence C.I.O. Information (Box 314, Folder 7)
    - Anti Union Session, 1962 (Box 314, Folder 8)
    - Union Contractors Housing Trade (Box 314, Folder 9)
    - Electrical Works, UEW (Box 314, Folder 10)
    - UE Letter & Petitions (Box 314, Folder 11)
    - United Engineering and Foundry Company (Box 314, Folder 12)
    - Ladies Garment Workers, International (Box 314, Folder 13)
    - Union, Correspondence General (Box 314, Folder 14)
    - Unions File I.W. Abel, President, United Steelworkers (Box 314, Folder 15)
    - Unions labor (Box 314, Folder 16)
    - Union Officials (Box 315, Folder 1)
    - Union Railroads (Box 315, Folder 2)
    - Teamsters Unions (Box 315, Folder 3)
    - United Auto Workers (Unions) (Box 315, Folder 4)
    - UN (Box 315, Folder 5)
    - U.N.I.C.E.F. (Box 315, Folder 6)
    - United Nations Material on (Box 315, Folder 7)
    - US Customs (Box 315, Folder 8)
    - United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (Box 315, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Pres. L.B. Johnson - News Releases, 1967 (Box 315, Folder 10)
    - United States Steel (Box 315, Folder 11)
    - United Steelworkers of America (Box 315, Folder 12)
    - United Steel Workers of America Democratic Advisory Council. "The Current Legislative Situation" (Box 315, Folder 13)
    - University of Pittsburgh (Box 316, File-cabinet 1)
    - Urban Renewal general (Box 316, Folder 2)
    - Urban Redevelopment Slum Clearance. Turtle Creek, Braddock, Duquesne, Dravosburg, McKeesport, Lower Hill (Box 316, Folder 3)
    - Urban Renewal Index, 1963 (Box 316, Folder 4)
    - Vista (Box 317, Folder 1)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation (Box 317, Folder 2-3)
    - Voting Record Holland (Box 317, Folder 4)
    - W -general (Box 317, Folder 5)
    - WABCO (Box 317, Folder 6)
    - Wafe Negotiations and Minimum Wage (Box 317, Folder 7)
    - Materials on Wages, Prices, Productivity (Box 317, Folder 8)
    - Wage Policy (Box 317, Folder 9)
    - War on Poverty (Box 317, Folder 10)
    - Washington (Box 317, Folder 11)
    - Water and Air pollution Federal Funds (Box 317, Folder 12)
    - Water Pollution (Box 317, Folder 13)
    - Welfare Program (Box 317, Folder 14)
    - Westinghouse (Box 317, Folder 15)
    - Vets GI, 1968 (Box 318, Folder 1)
    - V.F.W. Post 1135 (Box 318, Folder 2)
    - Victory Caravan (Box 318, Folder 3)
    - Viet Nam printed material and news releases (Box 318, Folder 4)
    - War in Vietnam (Box 318, Folder 5)
    - Viet Nam (Box 318, Folder 6)
    - Visitors Washington Office and Calls (Box 318, Folder 7)
    - Westinghouse Bettis Plant (Box 319, Folder 1)
    - Westinghouse Letters protesting against contract awarded (Box 319, Folder 2)
    - Westinghouse Mass Transit (Box 319, Folder 3)
    - Westinghouse Proposed transfer of employees to Friendship Airport and New Jersey (Box 319, Folder 4)
    - Westinghouse Strike (Box 319, Folder 5)
    - Westinghouse Tennessee Valley Authority Contracts (Box 319, Folder 6)
    - Wheat (for Russia) General (Box 319, Folder 7)
    - White House Conference on Education, 1965 (Box 319, Folder 8)
    - Women in Congress (Box 319, Folder 9)
    - Women in Community Service (WICS) YWCA Proposal for a Woman's Job Development training and placement center, Pittsburgh, Pa., May 11, 1966 (Box 319, Folder 10)
    - World's Fair (Box 319, Folder 11)
    - World's Fair Montreal., 1967 (Box 319, Folder 12)
    - Y-General (Box 320, Folder 1)
    - Yearbook Recipients, 1964-1966 (Box 320, Folder 2)
    - Dredging of Youghiogheny River Port Vue (Box 320, Folder 3)
    - Youghiogheny River (Box 320, Folder 4)
    - Young Democrats, 1965 (Box 320, Folder 5)
    - Youth Unemployment (Box 320, Folder 6)
    - Youth Corps (Box 320, Folder 7)
    - Youth Opportunity Center (Box 320, Folder 8)
    - Youth Physical Fitness (Box 320, Folder 9)
    - Yugoslavia Tito (Box 320, Folder 10)
    - Z-General (Box 320, Folder 11)
- Reports, V.
  The Reports Series contains Elmer J. Holland's reports and releases 1957-1966.
  - Monthly Reports, 1.
    The Monthly Reports contains Elmer J. Holland's reports and releases, 1957-1966.
    - Volume 1, #1-8, April 1957- November 1957 (Box 321, Folder 1)
    - Volume 2, #1-7, January, 1958-August, 1958 (Box 321, Folder 2)
    - Volume 3, #1-11, January, 1959 - December, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 3)
    - Volume 4, #1-8, February, 1960 -September, 1960 (Box 321, Folder 4)
    - Special report to postal employees, September 24, 1957 (Box 321, Folder 5)
    - Special report on labor bill (Box 321, Folder 6)
    - Special report on social security (Box 321, Folder 7)
    - Special report on education bill, September 15, 1958 (Box 321, Folder 8)
    - Special report on Unemployment compensation problem, March 10, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 9)
    - Special report continuing prosperity, April 2, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 10)
    - Special report Steel wages and anti inflation, July 16, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 11)
    - Special report on veterans legislation, October 6, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 12)
    - Special report on hospital and medical care for social security recipients, October 7, 1959 (Box 321, Folder 13)
    - Special report "Who Settled the 1959 60 Steel Strike" (Box 321, Folder 14)
    - Special report on social security legislation (Box 321, Folder 15)
    - Special report on "The control of inflation by increased interest rates", March 11, 1960 (Box 321, Folder 16)
    - Special report to "The Pensioners, June 27, 1960 (Box 321, Folder 17)
    - Special report (Expressing appreciation of re election), November 21, 1960 (Box 321, Folder 18)
    - Volume 5, #1-10, January, 1961-October, 1961 (Box 322, Folder 1)
    - Volume 6, #1-7, January, 1962- September, 1962 (Box 322, Folder 2)
    - Volume 7, #1-7, February, 1963 -December, 1963 (Box 322, Folder 3)
    - Volume 8, #3-6, June, 1964 -October, 1964 (Box 322, Folder 4)
    - Volume 9, #1, March, 1965 (Box 322, Folder 5)
    - Volume 10, #1-3, January, 1966-October, 1966 (Box 322, Folder 6)
  - Material Relating to Monthly Reports, 2.
    - Report correspondence (Box 323, Folder 1)
    - Report comments favorable (Box 323, Folder 2)
    - Report comments unfavorable (Box 323, Folder 3)
    - Clippings on reports (Box 323, Folder 4)
    - Labor Union Officials Report mailing list (Box 323, Folder 5)
    - Mailing list (Box 323, Folder 6)
    - Blanks for submitting names for report (Box 323, Folder 7)
    - Expenses report (Box 323, Folder 8)
    - Reference material used in Reports (Box 324, Folder 1)
    - Report material (Box 324, Folder 2-4)
- News Releases, VI.
  The News Releases Series contains new releases, 1956-1968.
  - News releases, 1956 (Box 325, Folder 1)
  - January and February, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 2)
  - March and April, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 3)
  - May and June, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 4)
  - July and August, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 5)
  - September and October, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 6)
  - November and December, 1957 (Box 325, Folder 7)
  - January and February, 1958 (Box 325, Folder 8)
  - March and April and May, 1958 (Box 325, Folder 9)
  - June -December, 1958 (Box 325, Folder 10)
  - News Releases, 1959 (Box 325, Folder 11)
  - News Releases, 1960 (Box 325, Folder 12)
  - News Releases, 1961 (Box 325, Folder 13)
  - News Releases, 1962 (Box 325, Folder 14)
  - News Releases, 1963 (Box 325, Folder 15)
  - News Releases, 1963 (Box 326, Folder 1)
  - News Releases, 1964 (Box 326, Folder 2)
  - News Releases, 1965 (Box 326, Folder 3)
  - News Releases, 1966 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - News Releases, 1967 (Box 327, Folder 2)
  - News Releases, 1968 (Box 327, Folder 3)
- Card Files, VII.
  The Card Files Series contains sample materials given to constituents when visiting Elmer J. Holland's office and correspondence with Vera Buchanan, 1953-1954.
  - Constituent Name File (Box 328)
    Requests by constituent and action taken.
  - Flag File (Box 328)
    Card file listing all flags donated by Congressman Holland.
- Sample Materials, VIII.
  - Sample materials given to constituents when visiting the office (Box 328)
- Vera Buchanan, IX.
  Requests for aid and action taken by Mrs. Buchanan, immediate predecessor of EJH as congressman from district.
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 328)